Guide to the Leonid M. Ozernoy papers, 1960-2002
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Leonid M. Ozernoy papers
1960-2002
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Leonid M. Ozernoy, 1939-2002
C0083
16.5 linear feet (32 boxes)
Collection contains original research materials and published papers of Leonid M. Ozernoy.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Maryanne Ozernoy in 2004.
Biographical Information
Born in 1939, Leonid M. Ozernoy taught in the School of Computational Sciences and Informatics at GMU from 1993 to 2002. Born in Moscow, Ozernoy was one of the former Soviet Union's refusniks and came to the United States in 1986. He worked at Boston University and Harvard University before coming to the Washington, D.C., area in the early 1990s to join NASA's Goddard Space Flight Center in Maryland as a consultant. At George Mason, he taught courses in computational sciences and physics, such as Colloquium on Computational Sciences and Informatics, Astrophysics, and Modern Astronomy. Ozernoy's research involved the dynamics and structure of interplanetary dust, the physics of nonthermal processes in active galaxies and quasars, the dynamics of compact stellar systems, astrophysics of black holes, the formation of galaxies and large-scale structures in the universe, and observational cosmology. Ozernoy's honors included election as Fellow of the American Physical Society and Fellow of the Royal Astronomical Society in London. He also received the National Research Council-NASA Research Associateship Award in 1991. He died in 2002.
Scope and Content
Collection contains original research materials and published papers of Leonid M. Ozernoy. Also there are 20 35mm color slides on the solar system.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by subject.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds personal paper collections from many other George Mason University professors.
Index Terms
Persons:
Ozernoi, L. M. (Leonid Moiseevich)
Subjects:
Astronomy.; Astrophysics.; Computational sciences.
Contents List
- Leonid M. Ozernoy papers
  - Statement of Prospective Personal Research Program (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Job Register (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Job (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Friedrich Schiller university (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - OFB w/ Biermann (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - With Fridmann (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - OFB CSI - Physics Dept (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hydronamics of Giant Plant Formation (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Angular Momentum Transport (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Astronomy and Astrophysics (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Students Work (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fig. 1 to OFG (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ozernoy - Html Home Directory (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Beginners Html (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Astronomy and Internet (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Report on the work done by Ozernoy. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Replacement AAS meeting Registration Form (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Nature of SGRA (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Starburst at the Galactic Center (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - A Report on SGRA (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Computational Science Institute and Dept. of Astrophysics (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Astrophysical Journal (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Unorganized Papers (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - CSI Part Time Faculty Activity (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - AAS Notification Service (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Email Recipients (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Work done by Ozernoy (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Space Science Program Observatory Report (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Budgeting Report (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Proposals and Accomplishments (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Earth Observing and Space Research (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Quasi - Stationary States of Dust Flow (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Precision Measuring of Velocities Via the Relativistic Doppler Effect. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Structure of the Zodiacal Cloud (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Index of / Text-Archive / Macros / Latex / Contrib (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Imaging a Quasar Accretion Disk w/ Microlensing (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Astro Journals [1 of 3] (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Astro Journals [2 of 3] (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Astro Journals [3 of 3] (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Who's Who in Science and Engineering (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Gamma Ray Burst from Evolved Galactic Nuclei (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "Is the Great Wall Produced by Domain Walls" (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Periodicities (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Stratified very Large Scale Structure (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Astronomy 219 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Astronomy and Astrophysics Lecture Notes [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Astronomy and Astrophysics Lecture Notes [Folder 2 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Emails and Notes (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Sub - MM Cosmology (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Cloudy Disks [Folder 1 of 2]. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Cloudy Disks [Folder 2 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - QSS/AGN and HASPOCRU (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - MD 97 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - WAAM 3/27/96 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 4Th Compton Symp (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Research Summaries and Acceptance Forms (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Project Notes (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Computational Sciences and Informatics CSI - 889 Fall Course [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Computational Sciences and Informatics CSI - 889 Fall Course [Folder 2 of 2] (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - CSI - 889 Over - Head Notes (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Lecture Notes CSI - 889 [Folder 1 of 3] (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Lecture Notes CSI - 889 [Folder 2 of 3] (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Lecture Notes CSI - 889 [Folder 3 of 3] (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Synchrotron Emission of Jets [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Synchrotron Emission of Jets [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - ASTR 328/530 Problems and Exams (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Jets Folder. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Quasi - Periodic Flashes and other Astronomy Research (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Binary Pair of SMBH (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Messenger (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Proposals (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Jets Folder (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Cornell University Loading Permit (July) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - ["General Relativistic efforts in Astrophysical Jets" Received May 25, Accepted August 23, 1991] (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Astrophysical Journal to Dr. L. Ozernoy Jan 1, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Receipt from East Hill Citgo (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Properties and Analysis of Elliptical Galaxies (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Properties and Analysis of Elliptical Galaxies I (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Jets 3 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Gamma - Rays from Jets (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Globular Clusters (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Globular Clusters (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Dynamic Evolution of Global Clusters (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Current Projects. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - OGU Colliding Winds (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - NGC 4258 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - NGC 4258 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - ADP Dirbe I (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - GRB's (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Multiple GRB (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Multiple Gamma Ray Burst from a Collapsing Nucleus (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - ADP (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - NSF / PLA Proposal (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - A 20 Upper Limit for Sgr A (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Misc (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Transparencies (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Current Projects [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Current Projects [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Black Holes and Supernovas (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Astronomy Stuff (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "International Astronomical Union - Special Issues: Preliminary Program of the XXIVth General Assembly, Manchester 7 - 18 August 2000". (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Nu SKin Policies / Procedures and SCS Colloquium S'02 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Current Projects (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Projects Ideas I (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Mars (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Ap J3 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Who's Who in America (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Multiple GRBs (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Multiple GRBs (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - The Galactic Center - My Recent Work (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Evolution of Globular Clusters (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "Fundamental Time scales in Star Cluster Evolution (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - "A New Approach to Dynamic Evolution of Interplanetary Dust" (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "Neutrino Dating of the Galaxy Formation Epoch" (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Gamma - Ray Bursts From Evolved Galactic Nucle" (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Workshops and Conferences (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Proofs for Correction (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Angular momentum Transport in the Central Region of the Galaxy. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Teaching (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Ozernoy [Russian Literature?] (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Micro QSS (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - The 2nd Annual October Astrophysics Conference in Maryland (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Russian Papers (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - North Carolina State University [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - North Carolina State University [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Post - Newtonian Theory for Precision Doppler Measurements pp 1 - 30 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Post - Newtonian Theory for Precision Doppler Measurements pp 48 - 50 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Post - Newtonian Theory for Precision Doppler Measurements of Binary Star Orbits (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - GMU Computational Science Institute (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - International Astronomical Union (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Info about Space Debris (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - XXIV IAU Manchester 8/7 - 18/100 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Transparencies (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Projects (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - More Transparencies. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Publications on Minor Bodies and Dust (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Making Waves (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Tenure Dossier for Leonid M. Ozernoy [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Tenure Dossier for Leonid M. Ozernoy [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Angular Momentum Transport in the Central Region of the Galaxy (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Studies, Abstracts and Conferences [1 of 2] (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Gamma Ray Bursts (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - GRBs from Dormant Quasars (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - dok. tax ApJ paper [Folder 3 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - dok. tax ApJ paper [Folder 2 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - dok. tax ApJ paper [Folder 1 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Studies, Abstracts and Conferences [2 of 2] (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Clusters (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Tidal Friction [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Tidal Friction [Folder 2 of 2] (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Star Collisions (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - AAS 186 6/95 SN - Driven Models for Lyx. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondences (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Notes on Galaxy (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Pulsars (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Neutron Stars (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Measuring BH Mass (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Neutron Stars (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Ozernoy Publications (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Collision less Evolution of Galaxies (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Flint Anderson Dr. Ozernoy Fall 2001 [GMU Press Release: Origins of water on Mars, Earth and Venus] Asrto 530 Final Exam (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Annual Reports (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - MD g8 grb - rate. tax (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Pulsar Winds [1 of 2] (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Pulsar Winds [2 of 2] (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Determining Pc, Vc, etc (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - After Gal lactic Core Collapse (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Dynamic Modelling of Cores [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Dynamic Modelling of Cores [Folder 2 of 2]. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Radial Pulsations of Stellar Systems (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Studies and Examination of Black Holes (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Astrophysics Over Heads/Notes (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - H2 as DM (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - SUBMM COSMOLOGY (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Ultra Hot Gas (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Lyman Bubbles as Progenitors of LSS (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Dust (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Hot Coronae [Folder 1 of 3] (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Hot Coronae [Folder 2 of 3] (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Hot Coronae [Folder 3 of 3] (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Primeval and Rejuvenated Galaxies (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Evolution of Galactic Nuclei [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Evolution of Galactic Nuclei [Folder 2 of 2] (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - OBSREPGO.tax (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Regularities in Red shift Distributions of Quasars and Distant Galaxies (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Respropl.tax. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Dynamics of Dense Stellar Systems (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Manuscripts [Folder 1 of 3] (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Manuscripts [Folder 2 of 3] (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Manuscripts [Folder 3 of 3] (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Ultra Hot Gas (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Class Notes on Astrophysics (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Masers (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Dynamic Modeling of the Galactic Center Region (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Galactic Center Notes (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Super massive Black Holes (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Galactic Center Nucleus (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Achievements and Writings [Folder 1 of 4] (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Achievements and Writings [Folder 2 of 4] (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Achievements and Writings [Folder 3 of 4] (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Achievements and Writings [Folder 4 of 4] (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - JETS (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Stellar Dynamics. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Dynamics of Stellar Systems (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - JETS - Counter jets (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Jets from Stars (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Mailing Lists (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - The New York Academy of Science (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - APS (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - IGPP (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - AAAS (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Astr. Society of the Pacific (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Dynamics of Galaxies (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - American Astronomical Society (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - JETS (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - TRIAXIAL SYSTEM (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - ANISOTROPIC MODELS (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Magnetically Driven Jets and Magnets [1 of 3] (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Magnetically Driven Jets and Magnets [2 of 3] (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Magnetically Driven Jets and Magnets [3 of 3]. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - 14th Texas Symposium on Relative Astrophysics (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Mail Concerning Astrophysics (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Planetary Society (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - NASA Astrophysics Greenbelt, MD (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Articles from the Astrophysical Journal [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Articles from the Astrophysical Journal [Folder 2 of 2] (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - RELATIVITY AND COSMOLOGY [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - RELATIVITY AND COSMOLOGY [Folder 2 of 2] (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - 113 Exams '01 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Work and Accommodations in Moscow, Russia (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Misc. Astrophysics (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Published Works in Astrophysics (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Overheads and other notes Galactic Centers (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Dynamic Evolution of Galactic Nuclei (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Center Engines and Black holes (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Anisotropic Beams (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Personal Misc. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Stelar and Cosmic Explosions (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Resource Material and Allocation (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - N Stars (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Newsletter and Abstracts (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Class Notes and Experiment Handouts (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Crab Nebula, Theses on Astrophysics in Harvard Smithsonian (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Evolution of Black-Hole and Clusters Email/Printouts (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - DM in S and E Gal's (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - DM in Galaxies of Various Hubble Type Gravitation Scattering (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - AAS 191 Jan '98 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Can a Young Pulsar Serve as a Source of Activity of the Galactic Center (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Star bursts and Bright Phase (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Relativistic Kinematics (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Poly Tropic - ISD thermal Sph. Stellar Systems (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Accretion Disks and AGN (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - DRIBE (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Unorganized Science Journals and Notes. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Comptonization (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Colliding Winds at the G.C. IRS 16 Complex (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Colliding with Winds (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - The Galactic Center as a Black Hole Constraint to its Mass (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Galactic Center - BH Mass Diagnostics (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Origin of the 051 meV annihilation line from the Galactic Center (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Galactic Center Misc (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Geminga (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Two - Component Model of the Galactic Center (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Magneto - Optics Improved Unified Scheme (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Break-up of Binaries a Massive BH (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - 177th AAS Meeting Philadelphia, Jan '91 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Compton Backscattering as a Thermometer (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Cosmological Masers (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Plasma Turbulatn Reutter (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Light Element Production (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Constraint From X-Rays (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Evaluating Mass from Radio Spectrum (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Fridman et al (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Light Element Production Abstract (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Evolution of Galactic Nuclei (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Records (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Who's Who 1993 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Acceleration of Relat. Electrons in AGN (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Honors Program (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Lectures of Relativity and Cosmology (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Lectures (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Lectures (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - COBE (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Prepnnf Exchange (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Lectures (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Who's Who (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Physics 428 Relativity and Cosmology (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Research Associate ship Award. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Ozernoy (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Personal (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Personal Records (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Joint Projects with NNG (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Special Activity (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Ozernoy Publications, 1962-1999 (Box 32, Volume 1-11)
    One volume includes 20 35mm color slides on the solar system.